[
    {
        "id": 201,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which data structure is best for implementing LRU Cache?",
        "options": [
            "Array",
            "Queue",
            "HashMap + Doubly Linked List",
            "Stack"
        ],
        "answer": "HashMap + Doubly Linked List"
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "What is the time complexity of Heap Sort in worst case?",
        "options": [
            "O(n)",
            "O(n log n)",
            "O(log n)",
            "O(n^2)"
        ],
        "answer": "O(n log n)"
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which traversal of BST gives sorted output?",
        "options": [
            "Preorder",
            "Postorder",
            "Inorder",
            "Level Order"
        ],
        "answer": "Inorder"
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which algorithm is used to detect cycle in a directed graph?",
        "options": [
            "DFS",
            "BFS",
            "Topological Sort",
            "Binary Search"
        ],
        "answer": "DFS"
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "What is the auxiliary space of Merge Sort?",
        "options": [
            "O(1)",
            "O(log n)",
            "O(n)",
            "O(n log n)"
        ],
        "answer": "O(n)"
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which data structure supports FIFO?",
        "options": [
            "Stack",
            "Queue",
            "Tree",
            "Graph"
        ],
        "answer": "Queue"
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which algorithm finds shortest path in weighted graph without negative weights?",
        "options": [
            "DFS",
            "BFS",
            "Dijkstra",
            "Prim"
        ],
        "answer": "Dijkstra"
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "What is the height of a balanced BST with n nodes?",
        "options": [
            "O(n)",
            "O(log n)",
            "O(n log n)",
            "O(1)"
        ],
        "answer": "O(log n)"
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which technique is used in Quick Sort?",
        "options": [
            "Dynamic Programming",
            "Greedy",
            "Divide and Conquer",
            "Backtracking"
        ],
        "answer": "Divide and Conquer"
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "topic": "DSA",
        "question": "Which structure is used for BFS traversal?",
        "options": [
            "Stack",
            "Queue",
            "Heap",
            "Set"
        ],
        "answer": "Queue"
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which SQL clause is used to filter groups?",
        "options": [
            "WHERE",
            "GROUP BY",
            "HAVING",
            "ORDER BY"
        ],
        "answer": "HAVING"
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which key uniquely identifies a record?",
        "options": [
            "Foreign Key",
            "Candidate Key",
            "Primary Key",
            "Composite Key"
        ],
        "answer": "Primary Key"
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which join returns matching rows only?",
        "options": [
            "LEFT JOIN",
            "RIGHT JOIN",
            "FULL JOIN",
            "INNER JOIN"
        ],
        "answer": "INNER JOIN"
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which command removes all records but keeps structure?",
        "options": [
            "DELETE",
            "DROP",
            "TRUNCATE",
            "REMOVE"
        ],
        "answer": "TRUNCATE"
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which normal form removes transitive dependency?",
        "options": [
            "1NF",
            "2NF",
            "3NF",
            "BCNF"
        ],
        "answer": "3NF"
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which index improves SELECT performance?",
        "options": [
            "Clustered",
            "Non-clustered",
            "Both",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": "Both"
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which constraint ensures unique values?",
        "options": [
            "CHECK",
            "UNIQUE",
            "NOT NULL",
            "DEFAULT"
        ],
        "answer": "UNIQUE"
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which function returns number of rows?",
        "options": [
            "SUM()",
            "COUNT()",
            "AVG()",
            "MAX()"
        ],
        "answer": "COUNT()"
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which command is DDL?",
        "options": [
            "INSERT",
            "UPDATE",
            "CREATE",
            "SELECT"
        ],
        "answer": "CREATE"
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "topic": "SQL",
        "question": "Which join returns all records from both tables?",
        "options": [
            "INNER",
            "LEFT",
            "RIGHT",
            "FULL OUTER"
        ],
        "answer": "FULL OUTER"
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which scheduling algorithm may cause starvation?",
        "options": [
            "FCFS",
            "Round Robin",
            "Priority Scheduling",
            "FIFO"
        ],
        "answer": "Priority Scheduling"
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "What is a deadlock?",
        "options": [
            "Infinite loop",
            "Processes waiting indefinitely",
            "Memory leak",
            "CPU idle state"
        ],
        "answer": "Processes waiting indefinitely"
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which memory allocation suffers from external fragmentation?",
        "options": [
            "Paging",
            "Segmentation",
            "Virtual Memory",
            "Cache"
        ],
        "answer": "Segmentation"
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "What is a semaphore used for?",
        "options": [
            "Memory management",
            "Process synchronization",
            "Scheduling",
            "Paging"
        ],
        "answer": "Process synchronization"
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which is NOT a condition for deadlock?",
        "options": [
            "Mutual Exclusion",
            "Hold and Wait",
            "Preemption",
            "Circular Wait"
        ],
        "answer": "Preemption"
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which page replacement algorithm is optimal?",
        "options": [
            "FIFO",
            "LRU",
            "Optimal",
            "Clock"
        ],
        "answer": "Optimal"
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "What is context switching?",
        "options": [
            "Changing process state",
            "Switching CPU between processes",
            "Memory swapping",
            "I/O operation"
        ],
        "answer": "Switching CPU between processes"
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which OS component handles memory?",
        "options": [
            "Shell",
            "Kernel",
            "Compiler",
            "Loader"
        ],
        "answer": "Kernel"
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which scheduling algorithm is preemptive?",
        "options": [
            "FCFS",
            "SJF",
            "Round Robin",
            "Priority (Non-preemptive)"
        ],
        "answer": "Round Robin"
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "topic": "OS",
        "question": "Which system call creates a new process?",
        "options": [
            "exec()",
            "fork()",
            "wait()",
            "exit()"
        ],
        "answer": "fork()"
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which layer of OSI model is responsible for end-to-end communication?",
        "options": [
            "Network",
            "Transport",
            "Session",
            "Application"
        ],
        "answer": "Transport"
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which protocol is connection-oriented?",
        "options": [
            "UDP",
            "IP",
            "TCP",
            "ICMP"
        ],
        "answer": "TCP"
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "What is the default port of HTTP?",
        "options": [
            "21",
            "80",
            "443",
            "25"
        ],
        "answer": "80"
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which device works at Network layer?",
        "options": [
            "Hub",
            "Switch",
            "Router",
            "Repeater"
        ],
        "answer": "Router"
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which protocol is used for secure communication over internet?",
        "options": [
            "HTTP",
            "FTP",
            "HTTPS",
            "SMTP"
        ],
        "answer": "HTTPS"
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "What is latency?",
        "options": [
            "Data size",
            "Delay in transmission",
            "Bandwidth",
            "Packet loss"
        ],
        "answer": "Delay in transmission"
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which topology has single point of failure?",
        "options": [
            "Mesh",
            "Star",
            "Ring",
            "Bus"
        ],
        "answer": "Star"
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which protocol resolves IP to MAC address?",
        "options": [
            "RARP",
            "DNS",
            "ARP",
            "ICMP"
        ],
        "answer": "ARP"
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which layer does encryption belong to?",
        "options": [
            "Transport",
            "Session",
            "Presentation",
            "Application"
        ],
        "answer": "Presentation"
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "What is bandwidth?",
        "options": [
            "Speed",
            "Delay",
            "Data loss",
            "Security"
        ],
        "answer": "Speed"
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which protocol is used to send emails?",
        "options": [
            "FTP",
            "SMTP",
            "POP3",
            "IMAP"
        ],
        "answer": "SMTP"
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which address is globally unique?",
        "options": [
            "IP",
            "MAC",
            "Port",
            "Subnet"
        ],
        "answer": "MAC"
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "What is subnetting used for?",
        "options": [
            "Increase IPs",
            "Reduce traffic",
            "Security only",
            "Routing"
        ],
        "answer": "Reduce traffic"
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which layer handles error detection?",
        "options": [
            "Data Link",
            "Network",
            "Transport",
            "Session"
        ],
        "answer": "Data Link"
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which protocol is stateless?",
        "options": [
            "TCP",
            "UDP",
            "FTP",
            "SMTP"
        ],
        "answer": "UDP"
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which device breaks collision domain?",
        "options": [
            "Hub",
            "Repeater",
            "Switch",
            "Cable"
        ],
        "answer": "Switch"
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "What is DNS used for?",
        "options": [
            "Routing",
            "Name resolution",
            "Encryption",
            "Authentication"
        ],
        "answer": "Name resolution"
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which IP class supports multicast?",
        "options": [
            "Class A",
            "Class B",
            "Class C",
            "Class D"
        ],
        "answer": "Class D"
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "Which protocol is used for file transfer?",
        "options": [
            "SMTP",
            "FTP",
            "HTTP",
            "SNMP"
        ],
        "answer": "FTP"
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "topic": "Computer Network",
        "question": "What is a firewall?",
        "options": [
            "Antivirus",
            "Security device",
            "Protocol",
            "Server"
        ],
        "answer": "Security device"
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "What is a transaction?",
        "options": [
            "Query",
            "Set of operations",
            "Table",
            "Index"
        ],
        "answer": "Set of operations"
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which property ensures all or nothing?",
        "options": [
            "Consistency",
            "Atomicity",
            "Isolation",
            "Durability"
        ],
        "answer": "Atomicity"
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which key can have NULL values?",
        "options": [
            "Primary",
            "Candidate",
            "Foreign",
            "Super"
        ],
        "answer": "Foreign"
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which anomaly is solved by normalization?",
        "options": [
            "Insertion",
            "Deletion",
            "Updation",
            "All"
        ],
        "answer": "All"
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "What is index used for?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Faster retrieval",
            "Backup",
            "Concurrency"
        ],
        "answer": "Faster retrieval"
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which isolation level is highest?",
        "options": [
            "Read Uncommitted",
            "Read Committed",
            "Repeatable Read",
            "Serializable"
        ],
        "answer": "Serializable"
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which is not a DBMS language?",
        "options": [
            "DDL",
            "DML",
            "DCL",
            "HTML"
        ],
        "answer": "HTML"
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which join gives Cartesian product?",
        "options": [
            "Natural",
            "Inner",
            "Cross",
            "Outer"
        ],
        "answer": "Cross"
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "What is deadlock?",
        "options": [
            "Crash",
            "Infinite wait",
            "Data loss",
            "Index issue"
        ],
        "answer": "Infinite wait"
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which command is used to remove a table?",
        "options": [
            "DELETE",
            "DROP",
            "TRUNCATE",
            "REMOVE"
        ],
        "answer": "DROP"
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "What is view?",
        "options": [
            "Physical table",
            "Virtual table",
            "Index",
            "Trigger"
        ],
        "answer": "Virtual table"
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which constraint enforces referential integrity?",
        "options": [
            "PRIMARY",
            "UNIQUE",
            "FOREIGN",
            "CHECK"
        ],
        "answer": "FOREIGN"
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which normal form removes partial dependency?",
        "options": [
            "1NF",
            "2NF",
            "3NF",
            "BCNF"
        ],
        "answer": "2NF"
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which schedule is serializable?",
        "options": [
            "Conflict",
            "View",
            "Both",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": "Both"
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which storage is volatile?",
        "options": [
            "SSD",
            "HDD",
            "RAM",
            "ROM"
        ],
        "answer": "RAM"
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which file organization is fastest?",
        "options": [
            "Sequential",
            "Heap",
            "Hash",
            "Indexed"
        ],
        "answer": "Hash"
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "What is cursor?",
        "options": [
            "Pointer",
            "Loop",
            "Temporary table",
            "Index"
        ],
        "answer": "Pointer"
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which command is DML?",
        "options": [
            "CREATE",
            "DROP",
            "INSERT",
            "ALTER"
        ],
        "answer": "INSERT"
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "What is metadata?",
        "options": [
            "User data",
            "Data about data",
            "Index",
            "Backup"
        ],
        "answer": "Data about data"
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "topic": "DBMS",
        "question": "Which lock allows multiple reads?",
        "options": [
            "Exclusive",
            "Shared",
            "Binary",
            "Dead"
        ],
        "answer": "Shared"
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which data type is immutable?",
        "options": [
            "List",
            "Set",
            "Tuple",
            "Dictionary"
        ],
        "answer": "Tuple"
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What does len() return?",
        "options": [
            "Type",
            "Index",
            "Length",
            "Value"
        ],
        "answer": "Length"
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which keyword is used for function?",
        "options": [
            "def",
            "func",
            "define",
            "lambda"
        ],
        "answer": "def"
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What is PEP 8?",
        "options": [
            "Library",
            "Compiler",
            "Style guide",
            "IDE"
        ],
        "answer": "Style guide"
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which is mutable?",
        "options": [
            "String",
            "Tuple",
            "List",
            "Int"
        ],
        "answer": "List"
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What does append() do?",
        "options": [
            "Add at start",
            "Add at end",
            "Delete",
            "Sort"
        ],
        "answer": "Add at end"
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which keyword handles exceptions?",
        "options": [
            "try",
            "catch",
            "handle",
            "error"
        ],
        "answer": "try"
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What is output of bool(0)?",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False",
            "0",
            "Error"
        ],
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which is used for inheritance?",
        "options": [
            "extends",
            "inherits",
            "()",
            "class"
        ],
        "answer": "class"
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which module supports regex?",
        "options": [
            "math",
            "re",
            "sys",
            "os"
        ],
        "answer": "re"
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What is list comprehension?",
        "options": [
            "Loop",
            "Short syntax",
            "Function",
            "Class"
        ],
        "answer": "Short syntax"
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which operator is floor division?",
        "options": [
            "/",
            "//",
            "%",
            "**"
        ],
        "answer": "//"
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What is lambda?",
        "options": [
            "Loop",
            "Anonymous function",
            "Class",
            "Decorator"
        ],
        "answer": "Anonymous function"
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which keyword stops loop?",
        "options": [
            "stop",
            "exit",
            "break",
            "end"
        ],
        "answer": "break"
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which function gives ASCII value?",
        "options": [
            "ascii()",
            "ord()",
            "chr()",
            "code()"
        ],
        "answer": "ord()"
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What is __init__?",
        "options": [
            "Destructor",
            "Constructor",
            "Function",
            "Variable"
        ],
        "answer": "Constructor"
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which library is used for arrays?",
        "options": [
            "numpy",
            "pandas",
            "math",
            "os"
        ],
        "answer": "numpy"
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "What does pass do?",
        "options": [
            "Skip",
            "Error",
            "Exit",
            "Return"
        ],
        "answer": "Skip"
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which file extension for Python?",
        "options": [
            ".java",
            ".py",
            ".cpp",
            ".js"
        ],
        "answer": ".py"
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "topic": "Python",
        "question": "Which loop runs fixed times?",
        "options": [
            "while",
            "for",
            "do-while",
            "foreach"
        ],
        "answer": "for"
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is encapsulation?",
        "options": [
            "Binding data and methods",
            "Inheritance",
            "Code reusability",
            "Multiple inheritance"
        ],
        "answer": "Binding data and methods"
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which OOPS concept supports code reusability?",
        "options": [
            "Encapsulation",
            "Polymorphism",
            "Inheritance",
            "Abstraction"
        ],
        "answer": "Inheritance"
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is polymorphism?",
        "options": [
            "One name many forms",
            "Code hiding",
            "Data binding",
            "Object creation"
        ],
        "answer": "One name many forms"
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which keyword is used to achieve abstraction in Java?",
        "options": [
            "class",
            "abstract",
            "interface",
            "extends"
        ],
        "answer": "abstract"
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which type of inheritance is not supported in Java using classes?",
        "options": [
            "Single",
            "Multilevel",
            "Hierarchical",
            "Multiple"
        ],
        "answer": "Multiple"
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is constructor?",
        "options": [
            "Method",
            "Variable",
            "Special method",
            "Object"
        ],
        "answer": "Special method"
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which concept hides implementation details?",
        "options": [
            "Polymorphism",
            "Inheritance",
            "Encapsulation",
            "Abstraction"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstraction"
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is method overriding?",
        "options": [
            "Same method name different class",
            "Same method different params",
            "Different name same class",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": "Same method name different class"
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which keyword prevents inheritance?",
        "options": [
            "final",
            "static",
            "private",
            "protected"
        ],
        "answer": "final"
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which binding occurs at runtime?",
        "options": [
            "Static",
            "Dynamic",
            "Early",
            "Compile-time"
        ],
        "answer": "Dynamic"
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is object?",
        "options": [
            "Class instance",
            "Method",
            "Variable",
            "Package"
        ],
        "answer": "Class instance"
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which feature allows same function name?",
        "options": [
            "Encapsulation",
            "Abstraction",
            "Polymorphism",
            "Inheritance"
        ],
        "answer": "Polymorphism"
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is interface?",
        "options": [
            "Abstract class",
            "Blueprint",
            "Concrete class",
            "Object"
        ],
        "answer": "Blueprint"
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which access modifier is most restrictive?",
        "options": [
            "public",
            "protected",
            "default",
            "private"
        ],
        "answer": "private"
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "What is method overloading?",
        "options": [
            "Same method diff params",
            "Same method diff class",
            "Override",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": "Same method diff params"
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which keyword refers current object?",
        "options": [
            "this",
            "super",
            "self",
            "object"
        ],
        "answer": "this"
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which supports loose coupling?",
        "options": [
            "Inheritance",
            "Encapsulation",
            "Abstraction",
            "Polymorphism"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstraction"
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which class cannot be instantiated?",
        "options": [
            "Concrete",
            "Normal",
            "Abstract",
            "Derived"
        ],
        "answer": "Abstract"
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which concept improves security?",
        "options": [
            "Polymorphism",
            "Inheritance",
            "Encapsulation",
            "Overloading"
        ],
        "answer": "Encapsulation"
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "topic": "OOPS",
        "question": "Which keyword is used to inherit class in Java?",
        "options": [
            "implements",
            "extends",
            "inherits",
            "using"
        ],
        "answer": "extends"
    },
    {
        "id": 901,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "What is 25% of 200?",
        "options": [
            "25",
            "50",
            "75",
            "100"
        ],
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "id": 902,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "If A is brother of B and B is sister of C, A is ___ of C.",
        "options": [
            "Brother",
            "Sister",
            "Cousin",
            "Cannot say"
        ],
        "answer": "Brother"
    },
    {
        "id": 903,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Average of first 10 natural numbers?",
        "options": [
            "4.5",
            "5",
            "5.5",
            "6"
        ],
        "answer": "5.5"
    },
    {
        "id": 904,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Find next number: 2, 6, 12, 20, ?",
        "options": [
            "28",
            "30",
            "32",
            "24"
        ],
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "id": 905,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "If 3x = 27, x = ?",
        "options": [
            "6",
            "9",
            "3",
            "12"
        ],
        "answer": "9"
    },
    {
        "id": 906,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Which is a synonym of 'Rapid'?",
        "options": [
            "Slow",
            "Quick",
            "Weak",
            "Late"
        ],
        "answer": "Quick"
    },
    {
        "id": 907,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "A train covers 100 km in 2 hours. Speed?",
        "options": [
            "40",
            "50",
            "60",
            "80"
        ],
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "id": 908,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Find odd one out: Apple, Mango, Banana, Carrot",
        "options": [
            "Apple",
            "Mango",
            "Banana",
            "Carrot"
        ],
        "answer": "Carrot"
    },
    {
        "id": 909,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Simple Interest on 1000 at 10% for 2 years?",
        "options": [
            "100",
            "200",
            "300",
            "400"
        ],
        "answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "id": 910,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Choose correct spelling",
        "options": [
            "Enviroment",
            "Environment",
            "Enviornment",
            "Environmant"
        ],
        "answer": "Environment"
    },
    {
        "id": 911,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "If today is Monday, what day after 7 days?",
        "options": [
            "Sunday",
            "Monday",
            "Tuesday",
            "Friday"
        ],
        "answer": "Monday"
    },
    {
        "id": 912,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "1, 4, 9, 16, ?",
        "options": [
            "20",
            "25",
            "36",
            "49"
        ],
        "answer": "25"
    },
    {
        "id": 913,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Antonym of 'Expand'?",
        "options": [
            "Grow",
            "Increase",
            "Shrink",
            "Enlarge"
        ],
        "answer": "Shrink"
    },
    {
        "id": 914,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Ratio of 2:3 equals?",
        "options": [
            "0.5",
            "0.66",
            "0.75",
            "1.5"
        ],
        "answer": "0.66"
    },
    {
        "id": 915,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "If A > B and B > C, then A ___ C",
        "options": [
            ">",
            "<",
            "=",
            "!="
        ],
        "answer": ">"
    },
    {
        "id": 916,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Which number is prime?",
        "options": [
            "9",
            "15",
            "17",
            "21"
        ],
        "answer": "17"
    },
    {
        "id": 917,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Choose correct sentence",
        "options": [
            "He go school",
            "He goes school",
            "He goes to school",
            "He going school"
        ],
        "answer": "He goes to school"
    },
    {
        "id": 918,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Area of square with side 4?",
        "options": [
            "8",
            "12",
            "16",
            "20"
        ],
        "answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "id": 919,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "Blood relation: Son of my father?",
        "options": [
            "Brother",
            "Uncle",
            "Cousin",
            "Nephew"
        ],
        "answer": "Brother"
    },
    {
        "id": 920,
        "topic": "Aptitude",
        "question": "If CP = SP, profit is?",
        "options": [
            "Loss",
            "Profit",
            "Zero",
            "Negative"
        ],
        "answer": "Zero"
    },
    {
        "id": 1001,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which HTML tag is used to create a hyperlink?",
        "options": [
            "<link>",
            "<a>",
            "<href>",
            "<url>"
        ],
        "answer": "<a>"
    },
    {
        "id": 1002,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which CSS property controls text size?",
        "options": [
            "font-style",
            "text-size",
            "font-size",
            "text-style"
        ],
        "answer": "font-size"
    },
    {
        "id": 1003,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which attribute is used to provide unique identity in HTML?",
        "options": [
            "class",
            "id",
            "name",
            "key"
        ],
        "answer": "id"
    },
    {
        "id": 1004,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which JavaScript keyword declares a variable?",
        "options": [
            "int",
            "var",
            "define",
            "let"
        ],
        "answer": "let"
    },
    {
        "id": 1005,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which HTML tag is semantic?",
        "options": [
            "<div>",
            "<span>",
            "<section>",
            "<b>"
        ],
        "answer": "<section>"
    },
    {
        "id": 1006,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "What does CSS stand for?",
        "options": [
            "Creative Style Sheet",
            "Cascading Style Sheet",
            "Computer Style Sheet",
            "Colorful Style Sheet"
        ],
        "answer": "Cascading Style Sheet"
    },
    {
        "id": 1007,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which JS method converts JSON to object?",
        "options": [
            "JSON.parse()",
            "JSON.stringify()",
            "parseJSON()",
            "toObject()"
        ],
        "answer": "JSON.parse()"
    },
    {
        "id": 1008,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which CSS property makes layout flexible?",
        "options": [
            "position",
            "float",
            "flex",
            "display"
        ],
        "answer": "display"
    },
    {
        "id": 1009,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which event triggers on button click?",
        "options": [
            "onhover",
            "onclick",
            "onpress",
            "onchange"
        ],
        "answer": "onclick"
    },
    {
        "id": 1010,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which tag is used for forms?",
        "options": [
            "<input>",
            "<form>",
            "<label>",
            "<textarea>"
        ],
        "answer": "<form>"
    },
    {
        "id": 1011,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which JS keyword is block scoped?",
        "options": [
            "var",
            "let",
            "function",
            "const"
        ],
        "answer": "let"
    },
    {
        "id": 1012,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which CSS unit is relative?",
        "options": [
            "px",
            "cm",
            "%",
            "mm"
        ],
        "answer": "%"
    },
    {
        "id": 1013,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which attribute submits form data?",
        "options": [
            "method",
            "action",
            "submit",
            "send"
        ],
        "answer": "action"
    },
    {
        "id": 1014,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "What is DOM?",
        "options": [
            "Language",
            "API",
            "Document Object Model",
            "Framework"
        ],
        "answer": "Document Object Model"
    },
    {
        "id": 1015,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which tag displays image?",
        "options": [
            "<img>",
            "<image>",
            "<pic>",
            "<src>"
        ],
        "answer": "<img>"
    },
    {
        "id": 1016,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which JS operator checks value & type?",
        "options": [
            "==",
            "=",
            "===",
            "!="
        ],
        "answer": "==="
    },
    {
        "id": 1017,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which CSS property hides element?",
        "options": [
            "display:none",
            "visibility:show",
            "opacity:1",
            "hidden"
        ],
        "answer": "display:none"
    },
    {
        "id": 1018,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which HTML tag is self closing?",
        "options": [
            "<div>",
            "<p>",
            "<img>",
            "<section>"
        ],
        "answer": "<img>"
    },
    {
        "id": 1019,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which JS function prints output?",
        "options": [
            "print()",
            "log()",
            "console.log()",
            "write()"
        ],
        "answer": "console.log()"
    },
    {
        "id": 1020,
        "topic": "Web",
        "question": "Which HTTP method is used to fetch data?",
        "options": [
            "POST",
            "PUT",
            "GET",
            "DELETE"
        ],
        "answer": "GET"
    },
    {
        "id": 1101,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is scalability?",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Ability to handle growth",
            "Speed",
            "Availability"
        ],
        "answer": "Ability to handle growth"
    },
    {
        "id": 1102,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which is horizontal scaling?",
        "options": [
            "Adding CPU",
            "Adding RAM",
            "Adding servers",
            "Overclocking"
        ],
        "answer": "Adding servers"
    },
    {
        "id": 1103,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is load balancer used for?",
        "options": [
            "Store data",
            "Distribute traffic",
            "Encrypt data",
            "Monitor logs"
        ],
        "answer": "Distribute traffic"
    },
    {
        "id": 1104,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which database is NoSQL?",
        "options": [
            "MySQL",
            "PostgreSQL",
            "MongoDB",
            "Oracle"
        ],
        "answer": "MongoDB"
    },
    {
        "id": 1105,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is cache used for?",
        "options": [
            "Backup",
            "Security",
            "Faster access",
            "Storage"
        ],
        "answer": "Faster access"
    },
    {
        "id": 1106,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which cache eviction policy removes least used data?",
        "options": [
            "FIFO",
            "LIFO",
            "LRU",
            "Random"
        ],
        "answer": "LRU"
    },
    {
        "id": 1107,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is API?",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Interface",
            "Protocol",
            "Server"
        ],
        "answer": "Interface"
    },
    {
        "id": 1108,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which improves availability?",
        "options": [
            "Single server",
            "Replication",
            "Caching",
            "Compression"
        ],
        "answer": "Replication"
    },
    {
        "id": 1109,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is microservices?",
        "options": [
            "Single codebase",
            "Monolith",
            "Small independent services",
            "Library"
        ],
        "answer": "Small independent services"
    },
    {
        "id": 1110,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which is stateless protocol?",
        "options": [
            "TCP",
            "HTTP",
            "FTP",
            "SMTP"
        ],
        "answer": "HTTP"
    },
    {
        "id": 1111,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is CDN?",
        "options": [
            "Database",
            "Cache network",
            "Server",
            "Firewall"
        ],
        "answer": "Cache network"
    },
    {
        "id": 1112,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which handles async tasks?",
        "options": [
            "Queue",
            "Stack",
            "Array",
            "Set"
        ],
        "answer": "Queue"
    },
    {
        "id": 1113,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is sharding?",
        "options": [
            "Replication",
            "Partitioning",
            "Caching",
            "Indexing"
        ],
        "answer": "Partitioning"
    },
    {
        "id": 1114,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which ensures fault tolerance?",
        "options": [
            "Single instance",
            "Backup",
            "Redundancy",
            "Compression"
        ],
        "answer": "Redundancy"
    },
    {
        "id": 1115,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which is write-heavy database?",
        "options": [
            "Redis",
            "MongoDB",
            "Cassandra",
            "MySQL"
        ],
        "answer": "Cassandra"
    },
    {
        "id": 1116,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "What is rate limiting used for?",
        "options": [
            "Speed",
            "Security",
            "Prevent abuse",
            "Scaling"
        ],
        "answer": "Prevent abuse"
    },
    {
        "id": 1117,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which stores key-value pairs?",
        "options": [
            "SQL",
            "Redis",
            "GraphDB",
            "RDBMS"
        ],
        "answer": "Redis"
    },
    {
        "id": 1118,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which metric measures uptime?",
        "options": [
            "Latency",
            "Availability",
            "Throughput",
            "Load"
        ],
        "answer": "Availability"
    },
    {
        "id": 1119,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which architecture is tightly coupled?",
        "options": [
            "Microservices",
            "SOA",
            "Monolithic",
            "Event-driven"
        ],
        "answer": "Monolithic"
    },
    {
        "id": 1120,
        "topic": "System Design",
        "question": "Which improves read performance?",
        "options": [
            "Indexing",
            "Normalization",
            "Locking",
            "Constraints"
        ],
        "answer": "Indexing"
    },
    {
        "id": 1201,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Choose correct sentence",
        "options": [
            "He don't know",
            "He doesn't know",
            "He not know",
            "He no know"
        ],
        "answer": "He doesn't know"
    },
    {
        "id": 1202,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Synonym of 'Abundant'",
        "options": [
            "Scarce",
            "Plenty",
            "Rare",
            "Small"
        ],
        "answer": "Plenty"
    },
    {
        "id": 1203,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Antonym of 'Success'",
        "options": [
            "Win",
            "Achieve",
            "Failure",
            "Progress"
        ],
        "answer": "Failure"
    },
    {
        "id": 1204,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Fill blank: She is ___ honest girl",
        "options": [
            "a",
            "an",
            "the",
            "no article"
        ],
        "answer": "an"
    },
    {
        "id": 1205,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Correct plural of 'Child'",
        "options": [
            "Childs",
            "Childes",
            "Children",
            "Childrens"
        ],
        "answer": "Children"
    },
    {
        "id": 1206,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Choose correct tense: I ___ him yesterday",
        "options": [
            "see",
            "seen",
            "saw",
            "seeing"
        ],
        "answer": "saw"
    },
    {
        "id": 1207,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "One word: Fear of heights",
        "options": [
            "Hydrophobia",
            "Acrophobia",
            "Claustrophobia",
            "Xenophobia"
        ],
        "answer": "Acrophobia"
    },
    {
        "id": 1208,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Meaning of 'Break the ice'",
        "options": [
            "Start conversation",
            "Anger",
            "Stop talk",
            "End meeting"
        ],
        "answer": "Start conversation"
    },
    {
        "id": 1209,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Choose correct preposition: Good ___ maths",
        "options": [
            "in",
            "on",
            "at",
            "for"
        ],
        "answer": "at"
    },
    {
        "id": 1210,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Synonym of 'Rapid'",
        "options": [
            "Slow",
            "Fast",
            "Weak",
            "Late"
        ],
        "answer": "Fast"
    },
    {
        "id": 1211,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Antonym of 'Accept'",
        "options": [
            "Agree",
            "Allow",
            "Reject",
            "Permit"
        ],
        "answer": "Reject"
    },
    {
        "id": 1212,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Correct spelling",
        "options": [
            "Recieve",
            "Receive",
            "Receeve",
            "Recive"
        ],
        "answer": "Receive"
    },
    {
        "id": 1213,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Fill blank: Neither he ___ I am wrong",
        "options": [
            "or",
            "and",
            "nor",
            "but"
        ],
        "answer": "nor"
    },
    {
        "id": 1214,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Choose correct voice",
        "options": [
            "He ate apple",
            "Apple was eaten",
            "He eats apple",
            "Apple eat"
        ],
        "answer": "Apple was eaten"
    },
    {
        "id": 1215,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "One word: Study of birds",
        "options": [
            "Zoology",
            "Botany",
            "Ornithology",
            "Ecology"
        ],
        "answer": "Ornithology"
    },
    {
        "id": 1216,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Choose correct conjunction",
        "options": [
            "Although",
            "Because",
            "And",
            "Or"
        ],
        "answer": "Although"
    },
    {
        "id": 1217,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Correct article: ___ honest man",
        "options": [
            "a",
            "an",
            "the",
            "no article"
        ],
        "answer": "an"
    },
    {
        "id": 1218,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Synonym of 'Brave'",
        "options": [
            "Coward",
            "Fearful",
            "Courageous",
            "Weak"
        ],
        "answer": "Courageous"
    },
    {
        "id": 1219,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Antonym of 'Permanent'",
        "options": [
            "Fixed",
            "Temporary",
            "Solid",
            "Strong"
        ],
        "answer": "Temporary"
    },
    {
        "id": 1220,
        "topic": "English",
        "question": "Choose correct sentence",
        "options": [
            "She do work",
            "She does work",
            "She done work",
            "She doing work"
        ],
        "answer": "She does work"
    }
]